<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blogs on AI and Networking</title>
    <link>http://zhangineer.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blogs on AI and Networking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.128.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 20:16:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://zhangineer.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Networking and LLM — Supercharge LLM With Domain Expert Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2024-05-05-supercharge-llm-with-domain-expert-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 20:16:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2024-05-05-supercharge-llm-with-domain-expert-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>System Instructions are more potent than you might realize
I have seen many posts from Network Engineers and Architects dismissing LLM’s ability to perform domain-specific tasks. While it is true that a generic LLM software like ChatGPT does not possess the same level of domain knowledge, it has a high potential to outperform humans if given proper guidance and some teaching.
In this post, I will cut through the noise and examine how to “teach” chatGP to answer domain-specific questions like an expert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking and LLM in the Age of AI — Pt. IV: Knowledge Retrieval using RAG</title>
      <link>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-12-10-networking-and-llm-pt4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 20:16:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-12-10-networking-and-llm-pt4/</guid>
      <description>Using RAG to Enforce ACI Policy Standards
Networking management can be complex and depends on accurate information to take necessary actions. Taking the wrong action can be costly.
Photo by Susan Q Yin on Unsplash
This article is part of a series. Here are the links to the previous articles
Part I — Introduction Part II — Exploring Basic Interactions Part III — In-Depth Analysis of ChatGPT’s Responses In this article, we’ll first briefly discuss the basics of RAG, the process, and the components that makeup RAG.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking and LLM in the Age of AI — Pt. III: In-Depth Analysis of ChatGPT’s Responses</title>
      <link>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-11-22-networking-and-llm-pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:16:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-11-22-networking-and-llm-pt3/</guid>
      <description>Analyze LLM responses and understand hallucinations.
Efficient Network Operation is about getting precise information without additional &amp;ldquo;digging in.&amp;rdquo;
This article is a continuation of a series following parts I and II. We will begin by analyzing several complex conversations and conclude with examples illustrating hallucinations.
Recap The previous articles covered the basics of instructions, prompts, context, function calls, and how all these components integrate.
We also reviewed the responses to a fabric health query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking and LLM in the Age of AI — Pt. II: Exploring Basic Interactions</title>
      <link>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-10-29-networking-and-llm-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 20:16:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-10-29-networking-and-llm-pt2/</guid>
      <description>Instructions, Context, Function Calling and Prompts
The most crucial information we must provide to any LLM chat model are the context, detailed instructions, and precise prompts.
This article is part of a series — You can find Part I here
Instructions Instructions play a crucial role in shaping an LLM into a valuable assistant. Their purpose is to set clear expectations and guide narratives and context, thereby reducing inaccuracies and ensuring more precise responses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking and LLM in the Age of AI — Pt. I: The Exploration Begins</title>
      <link>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-10-07-networking-and-llm-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 20:16:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://zhangineer.net/posts/2023-10-07-networking-and-llm-pt1/</guid>
      <description>A series to explore how to leverage LLM for networking tasks
The rise of chatGPT and large language models (LLM) has opened up the possibility of transforming various domains. However, networking remains largely unexplored.
In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the potential of LLMs to empower Networking Operations. No AI/ML knowledge is required.
For the Busy People - TL;DR For the Series LLM demonstrated significant promise in assisting with IT and networking configuration management and troubleshooting tasks.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
